现在我明白了
I see it now.
我不能让你走
I can't let you leave.
那就只能说声抱歉了
I'm sorry you feel that way.
该我说才对
I'm sorry too.
可怜的萨罗
Poor Salo.
那个不是杰斯
That isn't Jayce.
他在被另一个心智左右
But there is another will at work within him.
我隐隐约约 在入口关闭前听到了些什么
I thought I heard something just before the portal closed.
很古老 像是...
Ancient, like a...
像是有人在说话
Like a voice.
那个其实是一种非常高深的咒语
This is a sophisticated conjuration.
它是独一无二的 同时具备了 自我复制和自我湮灭的特质
A singularity, simultaneously self-replicating and self-annihilating.
我们从未遇过这么错综复杂的情况
We've never seen complexity like this.
形态完美
Flawless...
运转精妙
exquisite...
状态混沌
chaos.
? I wake up to the sounds Of the silence that allows ?
? For my mind to run around With my ear up to the ground ?
? I'm searching to behold The stories that are told ?
? When my back is to the world That was smiling when I turned ?
? Tell you you're the greatest ?
? But once you turn, they hate us ?
? Oh, the misery ?
? Everybody wants to be my enemy ?
? Oh, spare the sympathy ?
? Pray it away, I swear I'll never be a saint, no way ?
? My enemy ?
? Pray it away, I swear I'll never be a saint ?
? Look out for yourself ?
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第六集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
诺克萨斯向来奉行实力至上
Noxus prizes strength above all else,
并附有三项核心原则予以诠释
defining it by three core principles.
眼界 这是重中之重
Vision. The top of the triangle.
善于运筹帷幄 拥有能够掌控全局的智慧
Charting a course, and having the wisdom to navigate it.
这是你前行的基石 孩子
This form is your base, child.
要能看到别人所看不到的
Your eyes see what others don't.
魄力 让周围的环境为你掌控
Might. Bending your environment to your will.
虽然你的速度在提升 但最终你需要回归力量
Your speed is improving. But eventually you need force.
但用力过猛会暴露弱点
Too much force exposes you to risk.
确实
Indeed.
最后一项 是计谋
The last is guile.
如魅影般无踪 变戏法般灵巧 像幻术般莫测
Phantoms. Tricksters. Mages.
收起体面 卸下担当
Absent honor. Absent accountability.
记住 凯特琳
Remember this, Caitlyn.
眼里有通路 体内有热血 心中无禁忌
Tunnels in your eyes. Lava in your veins. Shadows in your heart.
这个就是战斗的真谛
This is the truth of combat.
而我发现了第四项原则
I've discovered a fourth principle.
其他所有原则都因它而升华
One that heightens all others.
那就是牺牲 从痛苦中孕育出来的
Sacrifice. The temper born of suffering.
你我感同身受 他人却难以体会
We understand it as others cannot.
我们一脉相承
We are kin.
抱歉打断一下
Pardon the interruption.
我追踪到他去了底城
I've tracked him to Zaun.
我们该去捕兽了
Let's hunt a beast.
蔚
Vi.
我一直盼着你能回来
I hoped you might return.
你个卑鄙无耻的叛徒
You filthy traitor.
是啊 那是我最糟的时候 糟糕透顶
Yes. That was me at my worst. Simply awful.
但曾经那个不堪的我 得到了先驱的救赎
But the Herald has freed me of my past self.
他给了我改过自新的机会
He's given me a chance to make amends.
欢迎你们的到来
All are welcome.
但烦请各位先把你们的武器交出来
But I must ask you to surrender your weapons.
这里是和平之地
This is a place of peace.
这就是先驱的愿景
The Herald's vision.
来吧 他正在等你们
Come, he's expecting you.
我们听说你能治病救人
We hear you can heal people.
维克托 你曾告诉过我 一切都是有极限的
Viktor. You once told me, all systems have limits.
他值得我冒险一试
He is worth the risk.
范德尔和怪物的心智 已经纠缠在一起 难以分离了
Vander's psyche is deeply entangled with that of the beast.
你怎么知道他的名字
How did you know his name?
他告诉我的
He told me.
以为你真能创造奇迹呢 也是全凭撞大运啊
Ask for a miracle healer, get a metal fortune cookie.
我看到了你们的父亲
I saw your father.
也看到了他心目中 你们这个小家和底城该有的模样
His dream of your family and vision of Zaun as it could have been, it was...
真是很美好
beautiful.
真能编
Cookie.
那你能救他吗
Can you help him?
我会尽我的全力试一试
I will do all in my power.
不过呢 我要提一个条件
However, I have one condition.
感觉不止一个吧
Looks like you got a couple.
你能为公社出不少力 爆爆
You have much to offer this commune, Powder.
你的才能应该用来建设 而不是用来破坏
Your talents can be used to build, instead of destroy.
我还是干我熟悉的事儿吧 谢了
I'll stick with what I know, thanks.
我的条件是入夜之后 必须将他关押起来
My condition is that he must be restrained at night.
我知道他的破坏力
I've seen the harm of which he is capable.
你怎么想呢
What do you think?
你真的在乎我怎么想
You actually want my opinion?
我向来最讨厌凭运气的事儿了
I hate fortune cookies.
一定会把你救回来的
We're gonna get you out of there, Vander.
? Can you find me? ?
? I'm not hiding ?
? All my memories ?
? Aren't mine now ?
? Not me ?
? Show yourself ?
? We're all creatures ?
? Who am I to you? ?
? Find the mirror ?
? See what I see ?
? Remember me ?
? Remember me I'm on my own ?
? Remember me I'm too far gone ?
? I couldn't see ?
? Remember me ?
? Remember me... ?
我的宝贝们
My girls.
? All my life, I couldn't breathe ?
? Remember me ?
? Ooh ?
? Ooh, ooh ?
来啊 抓不到我
(蔚奥莱 爆爆)
你还记得他们吗
Do you remember them?
我就记得妈妈身上总有一股味儿
I remember Mom's smell the most.
- 机油... - 机油味
- Axle grease. - Axle grease.
这个地方...
This place.
你觉得真的可以吗
Do you think it could actually work?
一个弱不禁风的铁皮机械先驱 打造的地下乌托邦
Underground utopia, run by a skinny tin Machine Herald.
那我不如坐等皮城 沦落成底城的样子得了
Maybe when Piltover slides into the sump.
如果我们留下呢 帮他们一把
What if we stayed? Helped them out?
我们
"We"?
前进
Forward!
停
Halt.
不能带武器
No weapons.
必须遵守先驱定下的规矩
I'm afraid the Herald insists.
容我试一试
If I may.
我想这位先驱应该是 我从前的一位学生
I believe this Herald may be a former pupil of mine.
一位科学家
A man of science.
让我先跟他谈谈
Let me speak with him.
今天晚上全体待命
Ready our forces for tonight.
我倒要去会会这位先驱
I should like to meet this Herald.
你也感觉到了 没错吧 能量在慢慢消减
You've felt it, haven't you? Your decline?
你的力量不是无穷的 它只会越用越少
Your power is finite, diminished by every use.
我一直在恭候您 博士
I've been expecting you, doctor.
维克托
Viktor.
难以置信
Incredible.
我是多么想透过你的双眼
What I wouldn't give to glimpse the world through your eyes.
去领略你所感知的一切
To know what you know.
他的追求使他误入歧途
His quest led him astray of any trodden path.
他的身影迷失在黑暗之中
His own shadow dissolved to darkness.
如今继续前行是唯一出路
Now the only course was forward.
而他唯一的温暖 是在梦中看她翩翩起舞
The only warmth, a dream of her waltz.
知识是一种悖论
Knowledge is a paradox.
你了解得越多
The more one understands,
越会意识到自身是多么的无知
the more one realizes the vastness of his ignorance.
他是绝佳的试验对象 不是吗
Marvelous specimen, isn't he?
他血液具有的再生功能 会让你的能力更稳定
The regenerative qualities of his blood will stabilize you.
极致的微光 能让海克斯科技发挥到极致
Apex Shimmer combined with you, the apex form of Hextech.
你这个想法会要了他的命
What you are suggesting would destroy him.
为了什么呢
And for what?
征服世界 还是为了满足好战者的贪婪
Conquest? The greed of warmongers?
为了成就你的大业
To complete your work.
为了完成我们的自我救赎
To save us from ourselves.
你必须活着 维克托
You must survive, Viktor.
你相信命运的说法吗 博士
Do you believe in fate, doctor?
冥冥之中一切自有安排
Our paths carved before us.
指引我们的是一只无形的手
Guided by an invisible hand?
那不是命运 是进化
Not fate, evolution.
大自然最伟大的力量 永远变幻莫测
Nature's greatest force, forever in flux.
不 进化是会有终点的
No. Evolution has a destination.
它不是为了对抗自然 而是为了超越自然
Not to combat nature, but to supersede it.
为了迎来最终的光荣进化
The final, glorious evolution.
而他也不是什么试验对象
But he isn't a specimen.
他是人 他需要我的帮助
He's a man. And he needs my help.
所以我不能为了达成你的目的 而牺牲他的人性
I will not sacrifice his humanity for your cause.
你可以走了
You may leave.
也罢 但你心里也应该很清楚
Very well. But I assume you understand already,
一旦你不在了 这里也将不复存在
if you perish, this community is soon to follow.
执行公务呢 是吧
On the job, I see.
你不该来这儿
You can't be here.
不知道哪儿冒出来个到处乱跑的
Oh. Here, like where I landed
富家小猫鼬把我生扑在这儿的
when this rich, unhinged mongoose just tackled me?
小猫鼬
Mongoose?
你的头发
Your hair.
看起来还挺油光锃亮的啊
You look like an angry oil slick.
少跟我卖乖 小蛋糕
Don't sugarcoat it, cupcake.
要抓谁啊
Who's out there?
我们在这儿追踪到了 某种新型的炼金武器
We tracked some sort of new chemweapon down here.
是一头凶残嗜血的怪物
A bloodthirsty murderous beast.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我是来这儿救我爸爸的
Trying to save... my dad.
维克托认为能把那个人 从怪物体内解救出来
Viktor believes he can save the man inside the beast.
要是成了 那头怪物对我们恐怕就失去价值了
If he succeeds, I'm afraid the creature's usefulness will be lost to us.
那我们就得跟他来硬的了
Then we'll have to force his hand.
我可以提取一种血清 这样就能让维克托无法得手
I believe I can craft a serum that will prohibit Viktor's success.
什么事
Yes?
是蔚
It's Vi.
小别重逢真是难得啊
So much for happy reunions.
干得好 凯特琳
Well done, Caitlyn.
是时候了
It's time.
真跟个泥鳅似的
Slippery as an eel.
就知道你能搞定的
I knew you could get it.
最近我也想了挺多的
Had some time to think lately.
自从你闯进我的生活里
Ever since you dropped into my life,
我就像是突然戴上了一副眼镜
it's like I put on glasses.
说不清是看得更清楚了还是更模糊了
Except I can't tell whether everything's blurry or clear.
你想不想听个笑话
Wanna hear a dumb joke?
一个多愁善感的前科犯 一个大块头的毛球怪
A sentimental ex-con, a giant furball,
和两个皮尔特沃夫的头号通缉犯
and two of Piltover's most wanted walk
走进了一个奇怪的地方
into a weird cult.
注意 笑点来了
And here comes the punch line.
蔚
Vi.
我对你可是充满了好奇啊
You've been quite a curiosity.
你俘获了凯特琳的芳心 算是助我一臂之力了
One who captured Caitlyn's heart. I owe you thanks.
没有你的一走了之 哪有我的可乘之机啊
Your absence provided a vacuum I was able to fill.
若不是今天这种局面
In other circumstances,
我很可能会将你收入麾下
I might have offered you a position in my organization.
坚韧如你 难能可贵
Your resilience is undeniable.
当然 这也很难成真
Of course, that won't be possible.
因为你肯定不会安分守己的
You cause too many complications.
你不能再让凯特琳分心了
Caitlyn must not be distracted.
你多虑了 她的心我分不了
Don't worry, she's not distracted.
我父亲让我明白了什么是信任
You know, my father taught me about trust.
他曾告诉我 想要获取信任 只要做三件事
He told me if I wanted it, there were three things I needed to do:
讲实话
Be honest,
对一个自以为是 满嘴跑火车的人
even if it means telling a self-righteous windbag
要让她知道她嘴有多臭
that her breath smells like a cesspool.
有耐心
Be patient.
这一点我总是做不好 现在被你绑着也算是帮我了
Mm, still haven't cracked that one, but being tied up sure helps.
那第三呢
And the third?
少说一点没用的废话
Just shut the fuck up.
整个裂沟到处都设有哨塔
The fissures are blocked by guard towers.
巡逻队会定时定点绕着公社巡视
Patrols circle the commune at even intervals.
她的侍卫布防在这里 这里 还有这里
Her personal guard are posted here, here and here.
他们想不到会后院起火
They aren't expecting trouble at home.
只需一个得当的时机 一点运气 外加...
With flawless timing and luck and...
一个吸引注意力的大动静
A big distraction.
不管你做什么 不要低估了安蓓萨
Whatever you do, don't underestimate Ambessa.
范德尔有麻烦了
Vander's in trouble.
我有个计划 但你肯定不会喜欢
I have a plan. You're not gonna like it.
没耽搁你太久吧
Hope I was worth your time.
我不会失败的
I won't... I won't fail.
是蔚让我来的
Vi sent me.
放心 我会救你出去的
I'm going to get you out of here.
安蓓萨那么信任你
Ambessa believed in you.
你死了 估计她会很难过的
Your death will be a deep cut.
休想伤害我女儿
Don't touch my daughter.
你
You.
我不会失败的
I won't fail.
我绝对不会
I swear it.
范德尔
Vander.
现在我终于明白了
I understand now.
那种符文样式背后的信息
The message hidden within the pattern.
以及我们公社失败的原因
The reason for our failures in the commune.
博士是对的
The doctor was right.
这一切在所难免
It's inescapable.
因为人性
Humanity.
这是我们的本质
Our very essence.
我们种种的情感
Our emotions...
愤怒
Rage.
恻隐
Compassion.
仇恨
Hate.
如同一枚硬币 一体两面
Two sides of the same coin.
不可分割又相互作用
Inextricably bound.
范德尔 不要
Vander, wait.
不
No!
伊莎
Isha!
那些指引我们通向至善的因
That which inspires us to our greatest good...
同时也造就了我们最大的恶
is also the cause of our greatest evil.
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻